# **GEORGE BERCZELY**

George.Berczely@novastone-ca.com | M: +34-680-858718 | Madrid, Spain |

# **Summary**

Senior executive with **multinational CEO and CFO experience** focused on CTO roles supporting companies achieve sustainable transformations. Passion and drive to **turn around organizations** or to achieve **high growth** by engaging the whole team, combining a **structured**, **analytical approach** with **operational execution experience**.

#### **Skills**

- Ability to design and implement holistic transformation programs
- **Cross-functional experience** in operations and sales combined with **big-picture view** as General Manager
- Ability to build strong management teams and to engage front line staff
- Drives growth and sales

- Passion for **continuous improvement**
- Experience in budgeting, cost control and cash flow management
- Excellent **communication skills** in several languages
- Adaptability, having lived in nine countries across Europe,
  Asia and the Americas

# **Experience**

03/2020 - 03/2022 McKinsey&Company Madrid (Spain)

# **Senior Vice President – McKinsey Transformations**

- Company Transformation specialist with a functional spike in working capital
- Part of a specialized team of consultants that support companies in achieving sustainable, largescale transformations or restructuring
- Special focus on working capital, especially accounts receivable and collections
- Industry Focus in Logistics and Telecommunications

01/2018 – 02/2020 DHL Express Mexico Mexico City (Mexico)

# **Chief Financial Officer (CFO)**

- Restructuring experience, deepened finance functional knowledge
- #2 role in an entity with over EUR 500m revenue p.a. and 7,000 employees. Finance function with 130 staff.
- Implemented cost control mechanisms to achieve financial objectives despite largely fixed costs and increasing dependence on eCommerce and its peaks
- Reorganized the Order to Cash systems and processes, offshoring Billing and Payroll, optimizing Collections
- Strengthened Query Handling in order to accelerate collections and improve customer satisfaction
- Drove Balance Sheet clean-up and upgrade of accounting systems
- Currently implementing fiscal and system changes

03/2014 - 12/2017 DHL Express Vietnam Ho Chi Minh City (Vietnam)

#### **General Director**

- Own P&L management and growth experience
- Responsibility for EUR 70m in revenue, 430 staff, 10 locations
- Developed and executed 5-year plan with EUR 12m in investments in facility and fleet (expanded gateway by 50%, opened new service centers, acquired new fleet, new corporate headquarters)
- Changed half the Senior Management Team and 25% of the middle management
- Strengthened on Employee Engagement, improving from 86% to 95% in four years, and ranked #1 in Logistics in 100 Best Places to Work
- Won six external awards in Customer Service in 2016 alone

 Revenue CAGR of 15% over 4 years, increasing revenue per Kilo by over 10% while reducing Cost per Kilo by 5% p.a., and growing market share by 5% in 4 years

08/2011 - 02/2014 DHL Express Asia Pacific Hong Kong (China)

#### **Vice President, Business Planning & Performance**

- Sales management experience across Asia-Pacific
- Established performance management tools and processes, especially focused on Sales performance, and intervened to support underperforming countries
- Established and managed joint ventures and other partnerships; renegotiated with or bought out agents in several countries in Asia Pacific
- Executive Director on the Board of Blue Dart Express (a publicly listed express company in India)

08/2009 - 07/2011 DHL Express Asia Pacific & Emerging Markets Singapore

#### **CFO – Network Operations & Aviation**

- First finance functional responsibility, consolidated function across two regions
- Managed a cost basis or EUR 1.5bn p.a. achieving budget targets, full accounting and reporting responsibility across various legal entities
- Renegotiated Commercial Air Lift contracts with main carriers in the region, reducing commercial cost per kg by 5-10%
- Merged the Finance organizations in Asia Pacific and Africa, Middle East, Central Asia, consolidating the Finance teams of Bahrain and Singapore

08/2007 - 07/2009 DHL Express Asia Pacific Singapore

#### **Vice President Margin Improvement**

- Cost reduction and operations experience
- Responsible for Controlling of Operations Costs across Asia Pacific (EUR 530m p.a.)
- Developed and rolled out a program which reduced operating costs by ~2% p.a. sustainably
- Short-term cost reduction by 15% in the wake of the Financial Crisis

03/2004 - 07/2007 Deutsche Post DHL Bonn (Germany)

#### **Director of Corporate Strategy**

- Corporate Strategy and M&A experience on a global basis
- Developed and implemented cross-divisional strategies for the group (e.g., Global Aviation Strategy for DHL Express and Air Freight Forwarding, China Strategy for Express and Logistics)

10/1998 - 02/2004 McKinsey&Company, Inc. Munich (Germany)

# **Engagement Manager**

- Consulting experience focused on Transportation & Logistics and implementation
- Managed the Program Office of the Post-Merger Integration for Deutsche Post and DHL, ensuring execution of programs and realization of financial benefits
- Supported the integration of Logistics companies acquired across Europe (responsible for Spain, Switzerland and Germany), standardizing processes and introducing cross-border services

# **Education and Training**

Fontainebleau MBA

(France), Singapore INSEAD (full-time program)

(Singapore) 2001

Regensburg

Bachelor in Business Administration

(Germany), University of Regensburg / Université Bordeaux Bordeaux (France) Functional Focus on Finance, Accounting, Taxation

# **Activities and Associations**

• Chairman of the Transportation & Logistics Sector Committee of the European Chamber of Commerce in Vietnam

• Member of Young Presidents' Organization (YPO)

# **Personal Information**

- Age: 48
- Austrian and British Nationality
- German, Spanish and English at native level, very good French, intermediate Portuguese, basic Mandarin and Vietnamese